<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Data Loss on NebulaBC</title><link>https://www.neb.cx/tags/data-loss/</link><description>Recent content in Data Loss on NebulaBC</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 16:34:42 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.neb.cx/tags/data-loss/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>What happened to the old neb.cx?</title><link>https://www.neb.cx/p/new-blog/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 16:34:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.neb.cx/p/new-blog/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://www.neb.cx/p/new-blog/cover.png" alt="Featured image of post What happened to the old neb.cx?" />&lt;h2 id="my-data-is-gone">My data is gone
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>On Wednesday, the 28th, I sat down at my computer for a bit of peaceful work on a personal project of mine. All was going well when I went to fire off a search on my personal SearXNG instance and was met by a browser error. I ignored it for a bit, assuming that it was just a bug and would recover. It did not.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Once I was at a good pausing point in my work, I went to SSH into my server to restart SearX. Huh, that&amp;rsquo;s odd. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t. This isn&amp;rsquo;t the oddest thing ever; the VM in question only had a few gigs of RAM, and it wasn&amp;rsquo;t the strangest thing for it to freeze up, though it hadn&amp;rsquo;t happened in quite a while. I decided to log into my web KVM interface to see if I could log in, so I went to cloud.oracle.com, put in my credentials, and was met by a page full of errors. What I came to find out through talking to support is that Oracle Cloud deleted my account and all of my data for&amp;hellip; no reason? None that they&amp;rsquo;re willing to tell me at least. Thankfully, all of my data was not stored on Oracle; part of it is stored on OVH and another part on Azure. The largest problem is that even my cloud infrastructure on other platforms didn&amp;rsquo;t work anymore since Oracle was the gateway for everything.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="what-did-i-lose">What did I lose?
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>In total, I lost:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>All of my websites that were associated with the NebulaBC username.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>All of the data from my git server that was not synced locally.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>A few Minecraft and other assorted game servers, a portion of which were not backed up anywhere,.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The database for my image server (the images are stored in S3).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Most of my hosted services.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>My email server.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>This is a common tale of putting all of your eggs in one basket. My data was fairly distributed between servers and even regions. This was not enough. What I really needed was data that was kept away from Oracle, and I&amp;rsquo;d personally say that my biggest mistake was using Oracle Cloud in the first place. They seemed like a decent platform at first, but it was a mistake to ever trust them in any capacity with my data. It is a mistake that I will not make again. Next time someone I know is looking for a cloud host, they will not even consider Oracle. I most certainly will not recommend Oracle in a professional capacity either. Their support was awful, and they deleted every last byte of my data without so much as an email first.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve now moved to a smaller host that is run by real people that I can email or call if there is an issue. I will also be keeping multiple full disk backups of my servers locally from now on to avoid this in the future.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>