<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>100DaysToOffload on NebulaBC</title><link>https://www.neb.cx/tags/100daystooffload/</link><description>Recent content in 100DaysToOffload on NebulaBC</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 18:22:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.neb.cx/tags/100daystooffload/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>GitHub pages... Should I get pro?</title><link>https://www.neb.cx/p/i-hate-github-but-it-feels-so-good/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 18:22:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.neb.cx/p/i-hate-github-but-it-feels-so-good/</guid><description>&lt;p>Once upon a time my blog page was just a &lt;a class="link" href="https://gohugo.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Hugo&lt;/a> static site&amp;hellip; wait, it still is. Well, either way, it was just running on a VPS and I just edited it through SSH+Vim. Now after my stuff has been mixed around, it&amp;rsquo;s running on GitHub pages. It&amp;rsquo;s been a very nice setup, since I can edit from any editor on any PC and push to GitHub with an automatic rebuild. I love this workflow, besides one slight issue.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I use a lot of drafts. Every post I make for a blog is going to have a draft, and may be written over multiple days. This git setup means that I am stuck either immortalizing my drafts in my git repo, or I have to stick to editing on one computer. Neither of those are good choices for me, so I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking of ways I can keep this workflow but make my repo private. Out of the options I&amp;rsquo;ve reviewed, I could:&lt;br>
a) Fork over $4 a month to GitHub for pro - This is not my ideal solution, I don&amp;rsquo;t like using GitHub at all, and want to pay them money even less regardless of if they let me make a private repo with GitHub pages.&lt;br>
b) I could set up a git repo on my server, and put it right in my NGINX site path. I could then make a cron job to rebuild it - This would probably be the most practical solution, that said, I&amp;rsquo;m not entirely focused with practical in this case. I like having a site that is hosted, and I am willing to pay a few dollars to have my site update right away and have a generally better experience.&lt;br>
and c) The last option I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking of is purchasing a &lt;a class="link" href="https://sourcehut.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>SourceHut&lt;/a> account and trying to migrate my blog to SourceHut&amp;rsquo;s pages/CI system - This is a very tempting option for me. SourceHut is a git platform built by &lt;a class="link" href="https://drewdevault.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Drew DeVault&lt;/a> and seems much more ethical than GitHub&amp;hellip; Now, I &lt;em>do already&lt;/em> run my own git server, and have for over two years. Although I&amp;rsquo;ve quite enjoyed that and it &lt;em>has&lt;/em> been a better solution than GitHub, I think that maybe SourceHut is worth a shot, especially since it includes a CI unlike Gitea/Forgejo. If it can properly build and serve my Hugo page, I will be content.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There may be other solutions that I can not think of, and there may be other software that I can self-host. If this is the case, and you can think of something that I should try, shoot me an email (editing: I actually don&amp;rsquo;t have an email server up right now. My discord is &lt;code>nebulabc&lt;/code>). I&amp;rsquo;d love to hear what&amp;rsquo;s out there, and there might be something right in-front of my nose. For now I&amp;rsquo;m going to be trying out SourceHut to see if it can do the job for me, if it can I &lt;em>may&lt;/em> consider moving my git content over, or at least mirroring my repos. SourceHut&amp;rsquo;s takes on a traditional git platform (like not including client side JS) are very interesting to me, but if anyone has any opinions on the platform, feel free to speak your voice. I will be doing more research before I settle on a &amp;ldquo;forever&amp;rdquo; host.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>100 days to offload</title><link>https://www.neb.cx/p/starting-100-days-to-offload/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 03:44:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.neb.cx/p/starting-100-days-to-offload/</guid><description>&lt;p>#100DaysToOffload is a novel challenge for bloggers, created by &lt;a class="link" href="https://kevquirk.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Kev Quirk&lt;/a>, in which you try to make 100 blog posts within a year. This is quite difficult, but I have an idea that it may be the push I need for me to actually keep this blog active. I think it might help with my writing skills too.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A while back I was browsing Mastodon and ran into 100 days to offload. I thought that it looked quite interesting, so I bookmarked it and left it dormant. Just recently I was going through all of my bookmarks and rediscovered it. Now seeing that it still seems worthwhile to me, I&amp;rsquo;m going to give it a shot this time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you read my post &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.neb.cx/p/new-blog/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>3/2/24 - What happened to the old neb.cx?&lt;/a>, you&amp;rsquo;d know that I had a technical disaster and lost my entire website and blog along with it. I think this may actually end up being an opportunity to review what software I use, and how I use it. For now, this will likely be the topic of my posts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I need a lot of work done to get my websites and infrastructure back to a spot that I am content with, so hopefully I can manage to take this blog (and you, reader) along for the ride.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>