<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Meta on NebulaBC</title><link>https://www.neb.cx/categories/meta/</link><description>Recent content in Meta on NebulaBC</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 03:44:51 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.neb.cx/categories/meta/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>100 days to offload</title><link>https://www.neb.cx/p/starting-100-days-to-offload/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 03:44:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.neb.cx/p/starting-100-days-to-offload/</guid><description>&lt;p>#100DaysToOffload is a novel challenge for bloggers, created by &lt;a class="link" href="https://kevquirk.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Kev Quirk&lt;/a>, in which you try to make 100 blog posts within a year. This is quite difficult, but I have an idea that it may be the push I need for me to actually keep this blog active. I think it might help with my writing skills too.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A while back I was browsing Mastodon and ran into 100 days to offload. I thought that it looked quite interesting, so I bookmarked it and left it dormant. Just recently I was going through all of my bookmarks and rediscovered it. Now seeing that it still seems worthwhile to me, I&amp;rsquo;m going to give it a shot this time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you read my post &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.neb.cx/p/new-blog/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>3/2/24 - What happened to the old neb.cx?&lt;/a>, you&amp;rsquo;d know that I had a technical disaster and lost my entire website and blog along with it. I think this may actually end up being an opportunity to review what software I use, and how I use it. For now, this will likely be the topic of my posts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I need a lot of work done to get my websites and infrastructure back to a spot that I am content with, so hopefully I can manage to take this blog (and you, reader) along for the ride.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>